hi today I'm going to do a classic
smokey eye I've done quick smokey eyes
before and colorful smokey eyes using
cream shadows like one cream shadow or
all different colors and today I'm just
gonna do a two color classic smokey eye
so for this type of smokey eye I'm gonna
use three products when you use a
brownie taupe eyeshadow and this can be
any kind of brownie taupe also going to
use a dark grey I'm using the dark grey
from this benefit palette and I'm going
to kind of mix those together and we're
just going to use a black pencil so
starting with the topi brownie shade and
a flat brush just gonna Pat that on all
over my eyelid this isn't too dark to
start with this one's actually matte but
you could use one that had a little bit
of very low-level shimmer and if you
wanted to but I wouldn't go too shimmery
if you're gonna do really classic smokey
eye so just Pat it all over my eyelids
and up to the socket line it's kind of
messy just slightly above the socket
line if you want to check if it's gone
up high enough just open your eyes and
look straight ahead and you'll be able
to still see a little bit of the brown
shade there
so next I'm gonna go in with the dark
grey shade I'm gonna put it on to a 2-1
7 brush so you want to think nice and
fluffy and then blend onto the back of
your hand so that you don't have too
much on your brush you can always pick
up later and then start to add the dark
grey into the socket line and onto the
outer edge there the outer corner so you
go on top of the brown and everyone's
eye shaped different so the best way to
do this is to keep your eyes open keep
looking ahead if your eyes are slightly
different shapes then again keep looking
ahead because you can check to see if
they're looking similar if your eyes are
hooded again you'll need to have your
eyes open and then once you've got a
good sort of positioning on it then just
start buff buff buffing away and what
makes a good smokey eye is a nice big
fat generous brush so nothing smaller
than a brush like this
and you can use even a bigger brush and
just keep lots of circles and really
really buffing and softening those edges
so I'm just adding a little bit more of
the dark to the outer corner so you can
build up slowly now I'm going to use a
completely clean paulla Dorf this is a
sheer crease brush it's just a bit
bigger and a bit fluffier than a 207
it's really good to keep a nice big
brush that's clean handy and you can
really go in and blend and smoke that
all out
so next I'm gonna use a black kohl
pencil I'm gonna use this all along my
upper lash line and just hold a mirror
really low down and look right down into
it and feel it really in between the
lashes doesn't have to be perfect we're
gonna blend it in a second anyway
likewise underneath you can do it as a
series of dots we're gonna smoke that
out too and if you want to you can go
into your lower waterline as well
depending on how big or small your eyes
are you have very small eyes just skip
that step and then using a mix of the
brown and the dark grey shade the taupe
you shade and the dark grey I'm going to
start to smudge in underneath so just
really smudging that : smoking it out I
haven't done my concealer and my base
yet so it doesn't matter if it drops
down because I'm gonna clean it
afterwards and that's definitely the
best way to do smokey eyes eyes first
skin later same on the top really smoke
that in and then apply a nice thickening
black mascara and you want to get right
down to the roots of the lashes and get
loads of impact there and curl them
first if you need to put plenty of
mascara on once you've done your mascara
you can clean up under your eyes so just
remove any of that gray and brown
eyeshadow that's dropped down
so it's nice and clean and patch up your
moisturizer and apply your base as
normal so I've done my base and
concealer as usual and I've also used a
little bit of powder next going back in
with the light brown shade well hardly
any actually just a fraction of it on
the brush it's got a really really
smudge in underneath and you need to do
this after you've concealed otherwise
you kind of have a definite line between
where the smokiness finishes and the
concealer start so we just want to
really smudge that all in you can use
q-tips cotton buds if you like and just
smudge smudge smudge munch and then I'm
just gonna freshen up that line in the
waterline and it's five if it gets a bit
smudgy if you want to use a waterproof
pencil or a waterproof gel you can but I
think you want it to look sort of
perfectly imperfect you don't want it to
be absolutely you know no sensuality at
all I think with a smoky eye you want it
to be smudgy and a bit lived in a little
bit I think it just looks nicer it looks
sexier looks more modern for brows with
a smoky I think they're more natural
they are if they're quite light leave
them it just looks a lot more modern
I've got a little bit of the brown and
the grey that I've just used on my eyes
I'm just gonna take that to fill in a
little bit there but more or less going
to leave them soft now for the rest of
your face you can do a couple of
different things I mean smoky eyes
classically go with a nude lip I'm just
going to apply this nice nude chubby
stick
and for me I need to put a little touch
of blusher on I'm going to use a benefit
dandelion so it's not super bright but I
think I just look better with a little
bit of color in my face and most people
do or you could just do a little bit of
sculpting or something otherwise it can
get a bit gothy a bit Stark which is
another look which is fine turns which
look you're going for and also it
depends what it's for I mean you could
wear smokey eyes during the day like
this as strong as this if you just put
less base on less powder less of a lip
you know you can play everything else
down looks really good and for the
evening you can do what I've done which
is just a bit more base and powder and
you know give it more of a polished feel
so that's a very classic smokey eye
or you can go much more dramatic and
evening with red lips and matching nails
I think a classic smoky eye works for
everyone wear it however you want